Golf. I don't get it.
Pointless, absurd,
repetitive activity...
Very good for clearing the mind.
All these stalls here?
Mental washing machines.
Van Pelt, what do we got?
According to his driver's license,
this is Micah Newton.
Murder weapon appears to be
the 5-iron there.
- No defense wounds.
- Or witnesses.
Coroner thinks he was struck
from behind while hitting balls.
Sunblock, hand sanitizer,
healthy snacks.
Somebody grew up
with a protective mother.
Another golfer found him
around 4:00 this morning.
Killer left the victim's golf bag
and wallet intact.
Cho's going through
the car now.
It's pretty early to go golfing.
Apparently 4:00 a.m. is the beginning
of the morning rush.
Place runs 24 hours a day.
Talk to the management
and have them give you
all the security footage
from last night.
Yes, boss.
- Jane, focus.
- Trying. There it is.
Very hard
to find the correct knob.
- On the victim.
- Ah. Sorry.
Yes, uh, he is a professional,
health-conscious.
When you factor in the specially
monogrammed windbreaker
and the iodine stains
under the fingernails
and the illegible scroll
on these scorecards
you can only draw one conclusion
our man here was a doctor.
Somehow that makes sense.
- A doctor with a problem.
- What kind of problem?
This impact label
was marking his shots.
And in this particular case,
the "x" doesn't mark the spot.
His shots are more
at the front of the club.
- What does that mean?
- Well, it means that he was...
"Slicing them.
Coming across the face."
Happens when you're
feeling stressed.
Lisbon, may I speak
with you?
We really need
to get you a bell.
I wonder, have you developed any theories
on where agent Hightower might be?
No.
Has she been
in contact with you?
You mean, have I had contact
with a wanted felon
without notifying my superiors?
No, I have not.
You spent a day with
Hightower's children at CBI.
What were they like?
I'll get back to you on that.
Excuse me.
Cho, what'd you find?
Victim's I.D. Badge
was in his briefcase.
He's a doctor
over at blessed sacrament.
Oh! You may touch
the hem of my garment.
- What's this attached to it?
- It's a radiation badge.
Monitors exposure to hospital radiation.
I'll have the coroner's office test it
when they do the autopsy.
I wasn't finished, agent Lisbon.
Agent Laroche, this is a crime scene.
I'm busy.
Curious... your disinterest
in finding Hightower.
Are you for real?
We've had to endure
your surprise visits for months.
You named your killer.
She's on the run.
Why do you keep showing up
on my crime scenes?
- Because this morning, I...
- I don't even want to hear it!
The second Hightower's
replacement is announced
I'm gonna put in a formal request
to keep you away from me.
As I was saying, this morning I was
assigned to take over Hightower's duties.
- Which include overseeing this team.
- Oops-a-daisy.
I appreciate your candor
and I'm going to honor your request.
- Agent Cho?
- Yeah?
I'm putting you in charge of the team
as of right now.
Agent Lisbon, you report to agent Cho.
Good day...
Hey. I talked to the team.
We figured it out.
What's that?
Well, you run the investigation.
Call the shots like usual.
- I'll report to Laroche.
- I appreciate the offer, but no.
- You're the boss. This isn't right.
- It's a direct order. You are in charge.
If I'm in charge,
I have to be in charge for real.
I will back you 100%.
You're a senior agent.
Show 'em what you got.
- You sure?
- I'm positive.
I'll clear out my office for you
this afternoon.
- I don't want your office.
- I told you, it's o...
I prefer no walls between me
and my team.
How'd it go?
- I'm in charge.
- Got it.
- Any orders, boss?
- No, really.
Lisbon didn't go for it.
I'm in charge.
Oh. Well, congratulations.
Let's break down the case.
All right. Lisbon, can you please fill in
the personal details you've learned?
Sure. Micah Newton, age 42.
He's survived by a husband.
He's an M.D. but he played mostly an
administrative role at the hospital.
And, Van Pelt, did you find anything
on the surveillance tapes
from the driving range?
No help. Cameras only cover
the parking lot and clubhouse.
Killer must have parked
on the street.
- Fingerprints on the club?
- None usable.
- We have a coroner's report yet? Okay.
- Yeah. Right here.
The, uh, blow to the head
caused an instant cerebral hemorrhage.
No surprises there.
But there were questions
about his radiation exposure.
What kind of questions?
Well, hospital personnel wear badges
to keep tabs on their radiation exposure.
Now according to Newton's badge
he was way over the limit
for this month.
With levels like that, he should
have been glowing in the dark.
But the coroner's test of his body found it
within an acceptable range.
How could that happen?
Lisbon, take Jane
to the hospital and find out.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll talk to the husband.
Van Pelt, check into Newton's records.
Rigsby, you're with me.
Okay.
You have a chance
to read the case files yet?
No need. I saw enough at the crime
scene to know that a doctor did it.
How can you tell?
A single blow to the head
causing instant death...
That takes medical know-how, a strong ego
and a killer golf swing.
Definitely a doctor-on-doctor crime.
Are you the CBI agents?
Yes, she does the detecting,
And I do the insulting.
- Consulting.
- That, too.
Francine Trent.
I'm Dr. Newton's assistant...
- Was, I guess.
- I'm sorry.
If you'll follow me.
Here's Dr. Newton's schedule
from yesterday.
Thank you.
According to this
the last appointment he had scheduled
to give a lecture at 8:00?
To the first-year medical students.
It was a highlight of his year.
I see you have the same
radiation badge he did.
We're required to wear them
at all times.
Any idea why his levels
were off the chart?
No. Um, we use radioactive substances
like cesium-137 for blood irradiation
but everybody wears lead shielding
so they're protected, so... I don't know.
Did you get an invite
to the wedding?
- I did.
- How was it?
It was lovely.
- Who are these people?
- Transplant patients.
Dr. Newton started the transplant board
at blessed sacrament.
Gave him tremendous joy.
- Are they still alive?
- Jane...
You're not my boss anymore.
Transplants are a tricky business.
But I-I've seen
so many people saved...
People who were going to die.
Yeah, well I'll let you in
on a little secret...
- We're all gonna die.
- I am so sorry.
That's okay.
Being scared of doctors and hospitals
is perfectly normal.
I'm not.
Um, so, uh, did he actually
go to his lecture at 8:00?
Yeah, he never missed
an opportunity
to give a motivational speech
to young doctors.
He was a good practitioner,
but a better leader.
I think it's why he moved
into administration.
And who's this rogue's gallery?
All the physicians
on the transplant board.
- Dr. Newton was chairman.
- Yet he stands to the side
and this man takes center stage.
Who's he?
Dr. Quick, chief of surgery.
As of this morning, he took over
Dr. Newton's responsibilities.
- Now we're getting somewhere.
- Can we speak to him?
He's leading
the transplant board meeting.
That's a fast transition.
Dr. Quick said the meeting
was too important to postpone.
- Will there be other doctors there?
- All of them.
A roomful of doctors?
Manna from heaven.
Could you please take us there?
I'll be on my best behavior.
I won't say a word.
Excuse me. David Vance,
event director?
Uh, he's in the back.
I'll go get him.
Thanks.
- So listen, delicate question.
- Yes?
Thursday quiz night is strictly
no bosses, as you know.
Should we give your spot
to Lisbon?
- Feels kind of weird.
- Do what you feel is right.
Or should we just hang on to your spot
in case you screw up?
It's just a joke.
Yeah. Funny.
You're gonna make a hell
of a boss man.
I'm already scared of you.
Thank you
for meeting me here.
I... I would have cancelled this gala
but it's my charity's biggest fund-raising
opportunity of the year.
When was the last time
you saw your husband?
Yesterday morning.
We're early risers.
Well, I'm the early riser.
My work is about an hour
from home
and Micah would just get up
to be with me...
even after a 12-hour shift.
Did you have any contact
during the day?
He called at 9:30.
Stressed, as usual.
Said he was gonna go to the driving range
- before he came home.
- Was that a normal routine?
Micah didn't like to bring
his work problems home with him
so he would sort it out
on the driving range.
So you think he was
facing a work problem?
Yeah, it was some kind
of personnel problem.
- Did he say what it was?
- No, no.
Micah's job came
with a bull's eye attached.
Somebody was always mad at him
for something.
Last week, this letter came from
the husband of a transplant candidate.
I thought you should see it.
Micah was head
of the transplant board.
He had to make hard decisions...
Who lived and who died.
I told him he should go
and take that to the police
but he said it was nothing
to worry about.
"If my wife dies, you're the
son of a bitch I'm coming for first."
Thank you.
We have a new patient at the top
of the kidney transplant list...
Patient Siberia.
His, kidney function's
at a critical stage.
Dr. Watson will give us a rundown.
Wh-What about Enid Jordan?
She won't last another week.
That's who Newton
had at the top of the list.
Due to tragic circumstances
Dr. Newton's no longer running
this meeting. I am.
And as a member
of the anesthesia service
Dr. Gidry, you are merely here
in an advisory role.
Watson?
Patient Siberia
has end-stage renal failure.
Yes?
Why do they call it
a kangaroo court?
Are kangaroos especially unjust
in comparison to other marsupials?
Would wallabies be more judicious?
You promised
you wouldn't say anything.
- He promised he wouldn't say anything.
- It's just a little...
- This is not a kangaroo court.
- Did I say it was?
Interesting that you deny
an unmade accusation.
- Now that you raise the issue...
- I'm sorry.
Who is this man?
Oh, he's Patrick Jane.
He's a consultant with the CBI.
- Hi.
- I'm agent Teresa Lisbon.
We're investigating
the murder of Dr. Newton.
- Well, this is hardly the venue.
- On the contrary. This is just the venue.
A roomful of professionals
who prescribe drugs
they know little about
to cure diseases they know less about
for people they know nothing about
and they call me a fraud.
Now by the raise of the hand,
which one of you killed Dr. Newton?
You're gonna stand by
and watch this?
Ah, it's out of my control.
My boss is agent Kimball Cho.
I can give you his phone number.
Well, I won't put up with it.
Oh, come, now.
It's perfectly obvious.
Patient Siberia gets first dibs
on a kidney
because he's some V.I.P.
with oodles of cash.
Now that you're in charge
it's all velvet rope
for the V.I.P.S, right?
Meeting adjourned.
Oh, and, uh, for those of you
who are less experienced
with police intimidation
you're under no obligation
to talk to these two.
- Smooth.
- Thank you.
- Give 'em hell.
- I will.
- You're Dr. Quick's accomplice, yes?
- Surgery fellow.
- Scared of doctors, eh?
- No.
I understand.
Don't like some of them myself.
Since Dr. Quick isn't interested
in talking to us
perhaps you can tell us
where he was last night.
You think he had something to do
with Dr. Newton's murder?
- Why?
- Elementary, my dear Vernon.
Newton's body isn't even cold
and quick has seized
his position with Gusto.
- The man lives up to his name.
- Dr. Quick didn't kill anyone.
He just wants us to be
a top-notch research hospital.
For that, we need money.
We're not a charity.
You still haven't answered
my question.
- Where was Dr. Quick last night?
- He had a dinner.
It was running late, so he
asked me to cover his call.
- I worked throughout the night.
- Late dinner.
You obviously haven't partied
with pharmaceutical reps.
- "Operator."
- We need Dr. Montez in I.C.U.
- And who's this patient Siberia?
- A kidney transplant candidate
who is patiently waiting
for me in the C.C.U.
- If you'll excuse me, please.
- "Dr. Montez to I.C.U."
"Dr. Montez to I.C.U."
Let's head over to radiology.
That badge is still buggin' me.
I wanna know why
it was so radioactive.
I'm gonna pass.
I'm off the cafeteria
for something deliciously
suspended in gelatin.
I'm not even gonna ask you
where you're really going.
You wanna know why?
I don't have to.
- Hi, Byron.
- Hey.
I'm agent Van Pelt.
- Your wife is Enid Jordan?
- Yeah, that's right.
Last week the head
of the transplant board
at blessed sacrament
received this.
Did you write it?
You know, they say if you're
angry to write a letter
but wait a day
before you send it.
They say sometimes just the act
of writing is enough.
I waited a week.
And I still felt every word.
So, yes, I sent it.
You do know that Dr. Newton
was murdered last night?
Yes, and I'm sorry about that.
But tragedy happens.
Ask Enid.
Why were you so angry
with Dr. Newton?
He put your wife
on the transplant list.
Do you know what it took
to get into his program?
First, Enid had to lose the required
weight through sickness.
And then she was too sick.
And then after that, can we
afford to maintain a new kidney?
Hoop after hoop after hoop.
- But she was put on the list.
- And nothing changed.
You're up the list one day,
down the next
never at the top, and always
there's someone else
that gets to go first.
I'm so tired, lady.
Byron, where were you
at 2:00 this morning?
I was, uh, bent over a toilet
holding my wife's hair back
while she spit up blood.
Stress ulcers.
And so back into the hospital
she went this morning.
Another de-clotting procedure
this afternoon.
How many times
can they cut her open?
"Operator."
Hi. We need Dr. Watson
in the O.R., stat.
- "Which room, sir?"
- Three.
"Paging him now."
"Dr. Watson to O.R. 3, stat."
You must be patient Siberia.
Yeah, well I... Oh!
No movement.
No.
Who are you?
And don't say "doctor."
Wasn't going to.
I'm Patrick Jane.
And I'm kind of...
Law enforcement.
You must be some kind
of Russian crime lord, yes?
- Where's your badge?
- Front vest pocket.
It's more of a laminate.
I-I didn't get the, uh...
I'm a consultant.
I didn't get the real shiny badge.
Who tells you
I'm Russian crime lord?
Your Sochi accent, the star tattoo
on your chest the bullet wounds
your thousand-yard stare.
I could go on.
Thank you.
Rubens.
- My name is Ulis Oratni.
- Yeah.
Why are you here?
Well, a doctor at the hospital
was murdered.
His name is Micah Newton.
And he stood between you
and a...
New kidney.
You think I killed him.
No. Obviously, you're not in good enough
shape for such strenuous activity
but possibly someone you know did...
Someone, uh, strong like bull.
How's your golf swing?
Give me club.
I will show you.
Got the pa...
what's going on here?
This... this man... he has a gun
and he pointed it at me.
He's very rude and that's not even
including the assault.
Sir, I'm with the CBI.
Is he telling the truth?
Get up against the wall. Go.
It's your colleague that's trespassing.
And he's put the safety
of this patient at risk.
His blood pressure's skyrocketed.
We're leaving,
but we're taking him with us.
Come on.
Oh, just one more thing...
What's the going price
for a kidney these days?
Is it an x-ray machine
or a new wing on the hospital?
Or does Ivan the terrible here
have Dr. Quick's niece
tied up somewhere
in some basement?
- Go. Now!
- Bye.
I just got off the phone with Interpol.
Yegor Golenka our Russian friend in holding,
has an extensive police record In Moscow.
I'm gonna have
a word with him about it.
What did you find out about Dr. Newton's
radiation badge at the hospital?
I talked to his assistant
then I asked around
in the radiology department.
Nobody could explain why his radiation
levels were so high. It's a mystery.
Did you find out what source
of radioactivity would affect the badge
and not the person wearing the badge?
No.
Okay. Van Pelt, follow up
on that for me, would you?
- Will do.
- I can handle it.
Don't you have to go
talk to your suspect?
Yes, boss.
We hear you're a violent offender
in Russia.
How'd you come by
your weapon here?
I can get you a translator
if you need one.
I understand.
Well, in that case, speak up and look me
in the eye when you talk to me.
Show some respect.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's try again.
- How did you get the gun?
- I found it.
These guns... they practically
grow on trees in California.
You know that in this country
you need to have a license
to have a gun.
And when you threw my colleague
up against the wall
and held him at gunpoint,
you committed a felony.
That means you go to jail.
Your prison system is, uh...
Like vacation in Russia.
But then who would
look after Mr. Oratni?
My replacement.
- You'd do anything for him, wouldn't you?
- Without hesitation.
- Would you kill for him?
- Of course.
Did you kill Dr. Newton for him?
No.
Where were you last night
between 9:00 and 2:00?
Watching over Mr. Oratni...
In his room.
All night.
Dr. Quick... he, uh, made special
provision for me to be there.
Since arriving in this country
I have not left the side of Mr. Oratni
for a single moment.
Until now.
That's the nurse's station there.
If you need anything else,
please don't ask me.
You got me in so much trouble
this morning.
I'm sorry, Francine.
Thank you.
"Paging Dr. Bender,
Paging Dr. Bender."
- Looking for a post-op patient?
- No. I'm, uh, looking for a nurse.
- Which one?
- You, actually.
You're in the seat of power here and
we all know who really runs a hospital.
Please? Can somebody please help me?
Will you help my wife?
She just got out of surgery.
She says her pain is unbearable.
Hang in there, baby.
Enid Jordan.
Did she get her kidney?
No, just another de-clotting procedure,
more tubes stuck in her body.
I don't know how much more she can take.
Dr. Gidry.
- Still rabble-rousing?
- Always.
She's post-op 15 minutes
after a de-clotting procedure
and severely agitated.
Okay. Mrs. Jordan, it's Dr. Gidry
Your anesthesiologist.
- Where are you on the pain scale?
- Oh, come on! She's in agony!
What does it look like?
I'm afraid your wife has reached her
allowable amount of post-op pain medication.
I need you to hang on
a little longer, okay, honey?
Push 10 milligrams of Valium
if she's still agitated in 20 minutes.
What is wrong with you people?
I'm sorry, baby.
I, I'll keep trying.
I'm not gonna give up.
Excuse me, ma'am, if... if I may?
You might wanna try screaming.
Often helps.
Excuse me?
Screaming. Expressing the pain.
Saint whoever-it-is would agree.
Screaming... it's therapeutic in itself.
Besides, it'll get you your drugs
a lot quicker.
- Who are you?
- Patrick Jane. Nice to meet you.
- Byron and Enid, yes?
- Yeah.
Scream. Try it.
- Russian doesn't look good for it?
- Nope.
- Hey, boss.
- Hey.
Hi.
I was looking into the radiation badge
and learned something.
Any access in the hospital after hours
requires employees to use their I.D.
badge to gain entry.
- That sounds promising.
- There's more.
Newton's badge usage the night
of the murder doesn't add up.
How so?
According to the security report,
he swiped his badge in radiology
at 8:05 that night.
But Newton's assistant said that
he was giving a lecture
to medical students
around that time.
Exactly. Kind of hard to be
in two places at once, right?
We'll run that down tomorrow
and see where it leads.
- Good work, Van Pelt.
- Good work.
Thanks.
Well, you were right.
The radiation badge was a clue.
Just doing what you taught me.
Running down all the angles.
Yeah.
Listen, boss...
Don't call me "boss."
I'm not your boss. You're my boss.
Give it a try.
Come on, little more than that,
little more than that. Everyone.
The girl's got pipes.
How does that feel?
- Feels good.
- Pretty good.
Scream a day
keeps the doctor away.
I would steer clear of the tall one,
if I were you.
Nothing but heartache there.
How did you know...
Oh, my God. I have been telling Gloria
he was a dog for weeks.
Yes, but he is a yummy dawg.
So level with me.
Most of the doctors around here...
- Terrible, right?
- No, some of 'em are keepers.
Dr. Newton was an absolute treasure,
bless his heart.
Who else?
On the principle that he with the whitest
coat hides the darkest heart
who do you think is the nicest,
sweetest doctor here?
- Dr. Watson.
That's interesting.
You think he's the killer?
Well, he is Dr. Quick's yes-man
and the supervising physician
for patient Siberia
so that puts him
right in the thick of things.
No. Dr. Watson is cute...
And nice.
I, I was working a double last night
and he got doughnuts for everyone
on the graveyard shift.
You mean, whilst he was covering
for Dr. Quick's shift
he went out and bought
everyone doughnuts?
You should be marrying him, Daisy.
Dr. Watson wasn't working here
last night.
He just... Stopped by.
Doctors really are the best liars,
aren't they?
So is Dr. Watson
working right now?
Yeah, but his shift
ends in a half-hour.
- You want me to page him for you?
- Oh, no, no, no. I'll find him.
It's been a lot of fun.
Everything we've said
is in strict confidence.
I'll make that official
by deputizing each one of you.
It's our little secret, ladies.
What is he doing
in this neighborhood?
That's what you're here
to find out.
Dr. Watson lied about
working at the hospital.
He merely did a drive-by
with doughnuts
in the middle
of the murder window.
Probably looking for an alibi.
Hospital's only a few minutes away
from the driving range.
Entering a sketchy building
with a duffel bag...
Possibly full of money
to pay off the killer.
That's your cue to be a hero.
I'll wait in the car.
- Thanks.
- Go get 'em.
- "Get away from me!"
- "Alcia, stop! Alcia!"
- Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
- CBI!
- Hands in the air!
- Help!
- It hurts!
- What's wrong with her?
She's a heroin addict
coming out of an overdose.
I need to continue helping her...
Now!
Should I call for an ambulance?
No need. Alicia? Alicia, it's okay.
It's okay. You're fine.
Another dose should do the trick.
- No!
- What is that?
Naloxone. Fastest way to strip opiates
from the system
reverse an overdose.
Always keep it handy
in my bag.
Good thing one of her smack
buddies called me in time.
This is more than altruistic.
Do you have an addict in the family?
My mother OD'd
when I was 12.
It's part of the reason
I became a doctor.
Why did you lie about
being in the hospital
the night that Newton
was murdered?
I was moonlighting
at a mobile clinic last night.
That's a violation of my contract
with the hospital.
I can't afford to lose my job.
I've got medical school bills
like you wouldn't believe.
Okay. Well, keep up
the good work. Rigsby?
I'm sorry. This man's still a suspect.
If Newton found out about his moonlighting
that could be motive for murder.
Newton knew.
He even came to the clinic
to keep his skills up
give back to the community.
Regular saint.
See? There you go.
It's obvious Watson here
is a diamond in the rough.
One doctor clear, a whole hospital
full of suspects to go.
"Dr. Staitman to I.C.U.,
Dr. Staitman to I.C.U."
Seven minutes.
I should have hurdled
that last gurney.
Right.
What? I ran track in high school.
The medical students I talked to said
that Newton's lecture started at 8:10
but his badge was swiped
in radiology at 8:05.
That means he had five minutes to make
the same trip that took you seven.
And I was running fast.
So Newton was either faster than you
or someone else was using his badge.
Somebody stole his badge, definitely.
What? I'm fast.
Because of his position
Newton's badge allowed him access
to every area of the hospital.
Valuable badge to have.
And over the last month
Newton accessed
the radiology department
three times as much as any other area.
But the people you interviewed in radiology
- said that Newton rarely spent time there.
- Exactly.
Somebody else was using Newton's
badge the night of the murder.
Show him.
Newton's lectures are videotaped.
This is a still image
hours before Newton was killed.
He's not wearing his security badge.
Was it reported stolen?
No, but we believe the badge was used
at the time
by someone he thought
he could trust with it...
Francine Trent, his assistant.
I ran her financials.
She used her credit card two hours ago.
- Bought a ticket at the main bus terminal.
- Let's hit it.
The women's restroom is clear.
Concession area clear.
Suspect spotted,
northwest corner.
Are you going somewhere?
What is this?
We know you stole
Dr. Newton's security pass
the night of the murder.
When did you return it?
Before or after you killed him?
I didn't kill Dr. Newton.
- You're gonna have to come with us.
- First we need to look in that case.
- Don't touch that!
- Okay.
- What's in the suitcase?
- Cesium-137.
The suitcase is lead-lined,
but if you open it unprotected
the material will get into your
marrow and mutate your cells.
That's what she was using
Newton's all-access badge for.
Those pellets sell for a small
fortune on the black market.
And that explains
all the radiology visits
and why, when I first met you,
you knew so much about it.
Did Newton find out you stole them?
Is that why you killed him?
I didn't kill anyone.
I, I spent the night at my boyfriend's.
You can check.
Rigsby, I want a Hazmat team
down here asap.
Van Pelt, keep the perimeter secure
and keep an eye on the suspect.
Lisbon. I don't think she's our killer.
How can you be so sure?
I believe her story,
and she's not a doctor.
You, too?
That's Dr. Malvo.
Needs to remind himself
which limb he's cutting into.
- Otherwise harmless.
- Unless you're his patient.
What's going on, Daisy?
He has enough drugs inside him
to knock out an elephant.
- It doesn't make sense.
- Sensing a pattern here.
If I had a nickel for every pain complaint,
I'd own the joint.
Wakey, wakey.
I heard they found you a kidney.
You all set for surgery?
Yep, I can see the fear in your eyes.
You have to be fearless
in your line of work
and now you fear the pain
you've inflicted on others
has come back to you
in the form of sickness.
And I do believe
you might be right.
Nothing like a fresh cup of joe
before you start the business
- of swapping out organs.
- Thank you, Patrick.
- Pleasure. And for the unsung...
- Patrick, you're too much.
I want a coffee.
You know, I have a very special
cup of tea here that you should try.
And our crack leader
who will presently save the life
of a ruthless foreign killer.
You definitely need a coffee.
You don't belong here. Henry.
Not very hospitable, but I get your drift.
Whoa, I'm leaving.
Your murder victim's assistant
gave up her buyer.
She's been stealing small amounts
from the hospital over the last month.
Adds up to a huge profit.
- The feds just picked the buyer up.
- That's a relief.
Unfortunately, she has an airtight
alibi for the night of the murder.
After she returned his badge
she did indeed spend the night
with a male companion.
So Newton's killer
is still out there.
True, but those pellets could have
been weaponized in a dirty bomb
with the power to injure
thousands of people.
Nice catch.
Wasn't my catch. Cho gets the credit.
He's a good leader.
You were right about him.
I'll include your sentiments in his file
as well as a commendation
in your own.
Thank you.
You are back in charge of your team,
effective immediately.
Wait... What?
- You're back in charge.
- I heard you.
Why was I pulled off
in the first place?
Maybe I was
messing with you?
And it showed you I won't
tolerate any disrespect.
That'll be all.
Lisbon, well done.
Very good news.
I have the perfect
congratulatory gift in mind
but you're gonna have to
come by the hospital
so I can present it to you.
"Patrick Jane, O.R. 8, stat."
"If you can hear my voice, Patrick
move your ass to O.R. 8."
Better make that quick.
That was my ass.
What the hell is this?
I felt it important
to let you and your team know
before you cut this man open,
that you have all been drugged.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean, drugged?
How? Who did it?
I did, by a special coffee blend.
I got the idea
from the able Dr. Watson.
What was that stuff you gave
to the heroin addict?
- Naloxone?
- Yeah, that's it.
It was handy in your duffel bag
just as you said.
I put a "carefully measured dose"
in the coffee pot... all of it.
Why would you do that?
Perhaps I should back this story up.
Somebody in this room is an addict
who's been stealing pain-relieving drugs
from the patients before,
during, or after surgery.
- What makes you think that?
- From my time spent with you, dear.
As soon as I saw those patients
fresh out of surgery
it was obvious to me they hadn't been
given enough of the good stuff.
And I believe that's what
Dr. Newton figured out
and that's what got him killed.
You drugged all of us,
based on that wild conjecture?
Yes.
- You gave everyone here naloxone?
- Yes!
Do you have any idea
how dangerous that can be?
Well, I did read the label,
thank you very much
and it's only harmful to those individuals
suffering with liver and kidney damage...
Uh, that makes Oratni completely
out of the question...
And pregnant women.
Oh, my God.
You gave me tea.
- Yes.
- How did you know?
It's perfectly obvious.
I also know who the father is
but don't... don't worry.
Your secret is safe with me.
Lisbon. Perfect timing.
Just in time to open your present.
- What's going on?
- I spiked the coffee.
Somebody in this room
is about to spiral into a rapid detox.
The shakes, nausea
those dreaded cravings
for the rush of a fresh hit...
- Hello. Someone's missing.
- I don't see Dr. Gidry.
The anesthesiologist.
Of course.
Lisbon. Hurry.
Drop the needle!
No, no, you... you... you don't
understand. I, uh, I need this.
- I'm going through withdrawal.
- No, you're not.
But the coffee...
Jane didn't put anything
in the coffee.
He needed to lure out the real killer,
and here you are.
Okay, okay. I-I-I admit it.
I-I-I stole drugs and I returned
them watered down, but...
That doesn't make me the killer.
Can we... can we just get...
get a little fresh air in here?
It's stifling.
Tell me how you started using.
Residency?
Up days at a time.
I mean how else were you supposed to
stay alert enough to perform?
And then I'd... I'd need something else
to help me come... come back... down.
And when did Newton figure out
you had a problem?
I don't have a problem!
I maintain perfectly!
No. Your real withdrawals
are starting.
You work with me here,
and I can get you what you need?
Last week...
Newton was doing
a review of O.R. cases
and he found some inconsistencies
in patient care.
So he brought you in.
He said that my actions had...
had left the hospital
exposed to lawsuits.
Zero tolerance means zero tolerance.
Blah, blah, blah...
So he fired you?
No, no, no, not just... not just
fire me, no. He... he was gonna...
He was gonna report me to the state
medical board. Huh?
And cooperate
with the police if asked.
He called it moral obligation.
I called it covering his ass.
So...
I tried to reason with him.
"After his lecture, you followed him
to the driving range."
I'm sorry.
"He said he was sorry,
but he just kept swinging."
"He was gonna destroy everything
that I'd worked for"
"but he kept on swinging,
and I lost it."
You killed him.
My life didn't matter to him.
Why should his matter to me?
So...
- Are you gonna help me out?
- No.
Got Gidry's confession.
Golenka's being deported tomorrow.
He'll be back just in time to greet Oratni
and his pre-owned kidney.
Now that quick's been fired for trading
an M.R.I. machine for a kidney
let's hope the hospital's transplant
program stays on the up-and-up.
Yeah, there's an endless supply of doctors
like quick in the world.
- Way to see the bright side.
- Need anything else?
I want you to know that my reinstatement
is in no way a reflection of your abilities.
- You did a great job.
- I know.
Hey, guys. Come on in.
So we have a question.
If there's a group hug coming,
I am so outta here.
No hugs.
We're going out for a drink
to celebrate the return of Cho.
You want to join us?
Guys, thank you. I can't.
I got a lot of paperwork to do
and there's a management meeting.
- Next time.
- Right.
- Good night.
- Next time.
- Night, boss.
The price of power.
Patrick. There you are.
Yep. Here I am.
You caught me.
Yeah. I, I didn't want to take up
too much of your time, uh...
I, I just wanted to let you know
that they found a kidney for Enid.
They're operating tonight.
I think your advocacy
had a lot to do with that.
Oh, no, no. Good for Enid.
It's... Good luck with that.
I wanted to give you this.
St. Sebastian.
Gave me a lot of strength.
Maybe he'll do the same for you.
A magical medallion.
That's... that's cool.
He helps people in pain.
But, uh...
You know, seriously, I'm...
I'm not really a believer.
You know what? Never mind.
Thank you very much.